Choose your destiny.
Wanted is a action, thriller, crime film directed by Timur Bekmambetov.
Doormat Wesley Gibson is an office worker whose life is going nowhere.
He meets an attractive woman named Fox and discovers that his recently murdered father - whom Wesley never knew -
belonged to the Fraternity, a secret society of assassins which takes its orders from Fate itself.
Fox and Sloan, the Fraternity's leader, teach Wesley, through intense training,
to tap into dormant powers and hone his innate killing skills.
Though he enjoys his newfound abilities, he begins to suspect that
there is more to the Fraternity than meets the eye.
Wesley Gibson, played by James McAvoy.
Fox, played by Angelina Jolie.
Sloan, played by Morgan Freeman.
Pekwarsky, played by Terence Stamp.
Cross, played by Thomas Kretschmann.
The Gunsmith, played by Common.
Wanted is a 2008 action thriller film directed by Timur Bekmambetov and written by Michael Brandt, Derek
Haas and Chris Morgan, loosely based on the comic book miniseries by Mark Millar and J.
The film stars James McAvoy, Morgan Freeman, Terence Stamp,
Thomas Kretschmann, Common, and Angelina Jolie.
The story of Wanted revolves around Wesley Allan Gibson, who decides to join the Fraternity, a secret
society of assassins, after learning that his father was a member of the Fraternity.
Universal Pictures acquired the adaptation rights from Millar in 2004, and while the eventual script drifted from the comic book
superhero mythos in the original miniseries, he was content to see most of the comic's darker content retained.
Production began in April 2007, with filming in the Czech Republic,
Budapest, and the story's main setting, Chicago.
Bekmambetov's production company, Bazelevs Production,
provided the majority of the film's visual effects.
Danny Elfman scored the film, employing a guitar-based musical score.
Wanted opened on June 27, 2008, to generally positive reviews with praise
for its fast-pace narrative and stylized action sequences.
The film grossed $342 million worldwide.
A sequel was announced shortly after the film's release,
but ultimately stalled in development.
The film explores themes of mission of murder, secret base,
secret organization, instinct, train crash.
The tone is intense.